As I was saying before I got
dragged away on another tangent and
I do realize when laughing
I am making light of something that
is obviously heavy for someone
right now on this planet
and I get that and it fluctuates
you know it's like weather for
example where I'm at
today is very rainy the air is cold
and wet and it's a unique kind of
day but it's chances
are it's not going to be like this
tomorrow same thing for yourself
you know you're having
a shit day blah blah blah you know
what tomorrow is another day and
today may not have gone
the way you wanted it to however
must be grateful for what you have
where you are in any given
moment people do a lot of time
traveling thinking about the future
and worrying about shit that
might not ever happen and run
themselves ragged I know I did it
hardcore since I was maybe
first grade kindergarten first
grade yeah and the anxiety is no
bueno but where the
hell was I going with this waking
up in the morning and the behavior
so I woke up this
morning and going about my day I
had a 35 foot long list of shit to
get done and going
about my business and I read
something that just for whatever
reason which when I do reflect
on it it is clear to me why it
triggered me but this specific
thing is not the focus of
why I'm sharing this it's more
about the behavior and so again
going about your business there
is a trigger that I run into a
stimulus a trigger and then there
is the response reaction
side of things and I didn't feel
the pause I just went right into
reactive and reactive
was a typical story a fiction a
manufactured scenario that is all
inside my head none of
its true it's as real as a doctor
Sue story and I'm not discounting
their anyway I don't
know what the fuck I'm saying there
point being I had a trigger and a
response without
any pause in it and it took me down
a very typical worn path and this
is a path mind
you I have done my whole life like
I mentioned earlier this is
something that I could insert
any trigger into this any behavior
into this and any you know reason
for doing said behavior
can also be inserted into this what
I'm talking about more is the
framework or the larger
architecture of the system at play
for people so when you're caught in
these loops the this
is the kind of high level system
you're caught inside of and
depending on what your scenario
is you know no one has the same
system just like no one has the
same biology story genetic
DNA mapping is identical I don't
even know if identical twins have
identical strips of
DNA of course that's my brain
wanting to go off and do another
research project and we're
not going there so continuing on
with the behavior so yeah this
behavior hit me you
know reflex instantly very much
like I was in the doctor's office
and had my knee got
tapped and I not a goddamn thing I
could do to stop it it just kicks
out it goes there
goes the response the a typical
annoying response and I you know I
get I go a typical annoying
I'm labeling it of course and the
labeling is because of my
displeasure with it because
I just don't like it it's behavior
that is detrimental to my well-
being and detrimental
to my nervous system which is very
important to me since it's been
pretty fried from when
I was young yeah so the I'm finding
that reflecting on it I'm more
annoyed that a I did it or
slash it happened and be I'm
curiously a bit upset with my
inability to have a high enough
level of awareness the proper level
of awareness basically what I'm
getting at is I didn't
have the right antenna set up to
pick up on it to see it before it
hits and that's basically
what played out and when that
played out I got stuck in that
pattern for two hours of
continuing to tell myself the story
and to the point where I was
unwilling actually there
was a part of my being that was
consciously unwilling to move that
next step forward which
I found quite interesting I think
it was the fear part of me that
typically gets to drive
the bus but no I consciously took
the next step and it turned out
that once I took the
next two steps everything that I
had dreamt up in those two hours
was make believe and
produced headache heartache high
blood pressure unhappiness to no
one but myself I share this
because I know the person listening
to this has had this experience
once at least once
maybe not intent very intense but
they're spent it's been there where
you have the reflection
and you go damn anyway my mind is
getting a bit ahead of my mouth
here and as my mind
is want to do it wants to go open
every door see what's behind every
single thing this
is interesting it's a blue
something out here in the middle of
the woods it's a t-shirt
I'm just going to leave that where
it is you can see it from the trail
and it does not
look like anything around it stands
right out so it's five feet from
the fire road and
they drive this off working very
hard on yourself being told you're
making progress looking at data
that's been
recorded objectively about you and
you're no part of that data
collection and that data
says you're getting better you can
feel that you're getting better and
all of those things
coming together in alignment
creates a energy of its own kind
it's a momentum and I've been
riding that momentum for the better
part of almost a week now tomorrow
will be well actually
today is day seven of the first
week of May it is the sixth but
technically it's the seventh
day I believe is it no tomorrow is
tomorrow's the one week anniversary
of my 57th birthday
and this past week has been pretty
tumultuous in terms of what's been
going on inside my
head it's almost like I need to
produce a weather report from my
head today it's looking
pretty stormy there Bert we're
going to have some showers coming
in from the east we expect
those to hang out for maybe an hour
or two and it should be partly
cloudy the rest of
the day until we get a little
sleepy for the evening and out you
go the brain weather report
brought to you daily there you go
come up with an AI that does that
for you so the feeling
better thing and the momentum thing
are important because they're very
real I felt it like an
energy sitting on top of my skin it
was an excitement that's how it was
it was a tangible
excitement on the surface of my
skin an example would be goose
bumps or some people call it
chicken skin you know the bald
chicken skin that's got the little
bumps on it and you
might get spooked out watching a
horror movie and get the chicken
skin or the goose bumps
it's akin to that because you get
goose bumps but you also get this
feeling and it's char
it's charged that feeling you feel
that I felt it when this kicked in
it was like turning
on an old fucking furnace and it
felt good quite honestly and I
burned a midnight oil
bit too much for like four days in
a row and did too much work kind of
burned myself out
a bit you are right there hi I'm
all right how about you so the
energy on the skin
was amazing and like any rush or
acceleration or excitement brought
brought on you want
it to continue it's like it becomes
an it became an addiction I wanted
to feel good
like that and keep working on
things and just get up and work on
my fun shit that I believe
has value stuff like recording
these things you know I've been
wanting to do this kind
of recording for decades and you
know it finally got to the point
where I thought to myself
what day is the best day to plant a
tree today you know it would have
been great two decades
ago if I had planted the tree and
started doing this my archive of
material would be
monstrous and the ability to cross
reference concepts phrases all that
good shit be pretty
cool gotta say so somebody who does
have a content archive of
recordings like this it
would be a lot of fun to throw an
agent on it and ask it obviously to
do at a base level
organize catalog tag etc so that
visually it's just easier to sort
things out but then
it can go a layer deeper which is
categorize and taxonomy by content
and by context perhaps
or something else who knows
thinking about the rest of today
and I actually back it up
so this morning after those two
hours and sitting there with the
realization that you
just did all of this to yourself
does bring about , so yeah, after
those two hours of spent energy.
It feels as though you've lived an
entire day energetically
psychologically you feel
not like I've lived a day but I've
lived 24 hours completely in two
hours.
It's that exhausting going through
that kind of shit at this time in
my life because it's
a triple whammy it's getting
triggered and pulled in that's just
annoying at a base level
number two is me you know basically
fueling the fire and keeping it
persistent and then
there's waking up to it and then
being upset with yourself once
again like you're upset
with yourself because you were just
beating yourself up just think
about that for a minute
you get upset with yourself because
you just caught yourself beating
yourself up you're
the only person involved in this
situation and no one is winning how
the hell can that
be that doesn't pass the Spock test
no way I don't think it ever will
captain well we
just figured out something new on
this star date there are no winners
in triggers that
create automatic patterned behavior
responses that adversely affect
your emotional psychological
being and your nervous system
because if you fucked around with
someone else's nervous
system the way that you do it to
yourself legally that might be pure
on harassment like
not just harassment emotional and
psychological torture what the hell
that is putting someone
psychologically through the wringer
I just walked up onto a bald eagle
that was interestingly
on the ground maybe eating
something got about 20 feet away
and it took off it had big wings
so it's a good thing that you're
not on the ground it's a good thing
that you're not
on the ground incredible what two
weeks will do and turn an entire
forest that is asleep
from its winter slumber gets turned
right on and there goes the bird
right back bird
thinks a damn teenage eagle just
landed on the path and walked back
across I'm a good
70 80 yards away so it feels a lot
safer I think I'm gonna end it
there and enjoy this
view maybe put this picture on this
post who knows